

Humberto Yusta Gómez

 $\begin{array}{c} humbertoyusta 02@\\ gmail.com\end{array}$

 $+53\ 55743975$

 $\begin{array}{c} {\rm Address} \\ {\rm Maceo~Street~\#20} \\ {\rm Zulueta,~Remedios} \\ {\rm Villa~Clara,~Cuba} \end{array}$

GitHub Profile humbertoyusta

LinkedIn Profile humberto-yusta-036710212

Humberto Yusta Gómez

CS Student, Competitive Programmer

About Me High school graduate with five years of competitive programming experience. Passionate about Math and Computer Science, looking forward to continuous learning, professional development, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Experience

2018 - Present, Competitive Programmer

Detailed achievements:

- <u>Bronze medal</u> at the International Olympiad in Informatics (<u>IOI 2020</u>) and best Latin-American score.
- <u>Master</u> at codeforces.com, <u>Yellow coder</u> at atcoder.jp, Platinum division at usaco.org
- Gold medal (3rd place), Bronze medal, and Silver medal at the Ibero-American Competition in Informatics(CIIC) 2020, 2019 and 2018 respectively.
- 3rd place at the 2020 ICPC Caribbean Finals (Qualifier), 6th place at 2019 ICPC Caribbean Finals. Participated as guest in both.
- Gold medal at the Cuban Informatics Olympiad in 2020, 2019 and 2018. 1st, 2nd and 13th place respectively.
- 8th place at the Asia-Pacific Informatics Olympiad 2021 Open Contest.

2021 - Present, Problem Setter & Trainer

Volunteer Work

- Problem setter, tester and staff member in the following contests:
 - Codeforces Round #768 (Div. 1, Div. 2), which had more than 26000 participants.
 - Ibero-American Competition in Informatics (CIIC) 2022
 - Ibero-American Competition in Informatics (CIIC) 2021
 - Cuban Olympiad in Informatics 2022
 - Cuban Team Selection Contests for the Ibero-American Competition in Informatics in 2021
- Author of three educational blogs on codeforces:
 - "XOR Hashing."
 - "K-th smallest edge on a tree's path, a tutorial about its approaches"
 - "Dp with connected components, a simple way to understand it."
- Personally trained the IOI 2021 Cuba Team for two weeks.

Education

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2020, IPVCE Ernesto Che Guevara

High School Graduate

Awarded as one of the best graduates of the Knowledge Contest Training Center.

Programming Skills

Programming Languages

 \circ C++ \circ Java \circ Typescript \circ Python

Development Software

Git
NestJS
PostgreSQL
Polygon